<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ScrollView xmlns:android="http://schemas.android.com/apk/res/android"
    xmlns:app="http://schemas.android.com/apk/res-auto"
    xmlns:tools="http://schemas.android.com/tools"
    android:layout_width="match_parent"
    android:layout_height="match_parent"
    tools:context="darkrai.lysis.corp.aidbot.BurnsActivity">

     <LinearLayout
         android:layout_width="match_parent"
         android:layout_height="wrap_content"
         android:orientation="vertical">
    <VideoView
        android:layout_width="375dp"
        android:layout_height="200dp"
        android:id="@+id/burns"
        android:layout_margin="10dp"
        android:layout_gravity="center_horizontal" />
    <Button
        android:id="@+id/textspeech"
        android:layout_width="50dp"
        android:layout_height="50dp"
        android:textAlignment="center"
        android:layout_marginLeft="150dp"
        android:background="@drawable/mic"/>
    <EditText
        android:layout_width="match_parent"
        android:layout_height="wrap_content"
        android:id="@+id/message"/>
    <TextView
        android:layout_width="match_parent"
        android:layout_height="wrap_content"
        android:text="Burns are injuries due to heat,chemicals,friction.
 Most commonly burns are caused due to exposure to fire, hot liquids and steam.
Chemical burns occur when the skin is exposed to chemicals.
 Burns can injure the layers of the skin and severe burns can affect the muscles, fat and bones.
It is important


to determine the extent of tissue damage before starting treatment for burns.
Categories of Burns

Burns are categorized depending on the severity of tissue damage.

    First degree - This is superficial and involves only the outer layer of the skin
    Second degree - This is a relatively minor, deep burn where the first and second layer of skin is burned
    Third degree - This is a deep burn involving all layers of the skin. In this case, the nerves, sweat glands, blood vessels are destroyed
    Fourth degree - This is a very deep burn extending through the skin into the subcutaneous tissue and muscle and bone

Symptoms

    First degree:
        Local inflammation of the skin
        Pain, redness and some swelling
        No blisters are seen
    Second degree:
        Pain, intense redness and swelling
        Blisters are seen
    Third degree:
        Lack of pain due to the nerve endings being destroyed
        Charring may be seen
        Blisters appear burnt
        Swelling
        Fluid oozing out
        High possibility of casualty going into shock
    Fourth degree:
        Charring may be seen
        Blisters appear burnt
        Area may appear white
        Bone may be visible

Action

    First degree:
        Cool the area with cool running water for about 15 minutes to stop the burning and relieve the pain
        Gently remove any jewellery, watches, or constricting clothing from the burned area before it starts to swell
        Cover the area with a sterile dressing, or any clean (non-fluffy) material to protect from infection. Wrap the dressing loosely to avoid putting pressure on burned skin.
        Do NOT use adhesive dressings
    Second degree:
        Remove casualty from burning area
        Cover the area (loosely) with a clean, wet cloth
        Keep the burned area elevated
        Do NOT use adhesive dressings
        Casualty needs medical attention
    Third degree:
        Remove casualty from burning area
        Casualty requires immediate medical attention
        Cover the area (loosely) with a clean, dry cloth to prevent infection
        Keep the burned area elevated
    Fourth degree:
        Remove casualty from burning area
        Casualty requires immediate medical attention
        Cover the area (loosely) with a large clean, dry cloth to prevent infection
        Keep the burned area elevated

Important: For deep burns

    Do NOT remove burned clothing
    Do NOT immerse burned areas in cold water
    Do NOT burst blisters
    Do NOT apply lotions, ointment, oil or butter to the burned area
"/>
     </LinearLayout>
</ScrollView>
